Guide to the Carl Van Vechten Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal Papers, 1879-1971; Series III; 39.5; 52 boxes
  - Albums and Scrapbooks
    - Carl Van Vechten
      - Volumes with autographs and photographic proofs of individuals photographed by CVV
        - "Volume Two", 1929–1933 (Box 198, Folder 2583)
          Accompanied by clipping regarding the death of Richard Haliburton
        - "Volume Three", 1930–1934 (Box 199)
        - "Volume IV", 1938–1941 (Box 200, Folder 2584)
        - "Volume V", 1941–1947 (Box 200, Folder 2585)
        - "Volume VI", 1948–1952 (Box 200, Folder 2586)
        - "Volume VII", 1952–1957 (Box 201, Folder 2587)
        - "Volume VIII", 1957–1958 (Box 201, Folder 2588)
        - "Volume IX", 1958 (Box 201, Folder 2589)
        - "Volume X", 1958–1962 (Box 202, Folder 2590)
        - "Volume XI", 1962–1964 (Box 202, Folder 2591)
        - "Volume XII", 1964 (Box 202, Folder 2592)
      - Cat clippings scrapbooks
        Includes newspaper and magazine clippings regarding cats
        - "I", 1919–1921 (Box 203)
        - "II", 1921–1924 (Box 204)
      - Fabric swatches scrapbook, undated (Box 205, Folder 2593-2594)
        Includes fabric swatches affixed to scrapbook pages, with labels indicating the storage location; accompanied by envelope of loose swatches
      - Homoerotic scrapbooks
        Include photographs by CVV and other photographers including Man Ray; drawings by Richard Banks, George George, Elwyn Chamberlain, and others; typescript jokes, limericks, etc.; postcards; magazines; clippings; brochures; and other material with homoerotic and homosexual content
        - Volume 1, undated (Box 206)
          Conditions Governing Access
          Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
        - Volume 2, undated (Box 207)
          Includes June 1921 issue of Rosener's Pan and The Courtship of Eumolpus (privately printed, 1928)
        - Volume 3, undated (Box 208)
        - Volume 4, undated (Box 209)
        - Volume 5, undated (Box 210)
        - Volume 6, undated (Box 211)
        - Volume 7, undated (Box 212)
        - Volume 8, undated (Box 213)
        - Volume 9, undated (Box 214)
        - Volume 10, undated (Box 215)
        - Volume 11, undated (Box 216)
        - Volume 12, undated (Box 217)
        - Volume 13, undated (Box 218)
        - Volume 14, undated (Box 219)
          Includes photographs by Man Ray; one signed, "Best Wishes 1933"
        - Volume 15, undated (Box 220)
          Includes photograph by Man Ray, signed
        - Volume 16, undated (Box 221)
        - Volume 17, undated (Box 222)
        - Volume 18, undated (Box 223)
        - Loose scrapbook material, circa 1950-1961 (Box 224, Folder 2595-2604)
          Includes pen and ink and watercolor drawings by Richard Banks; photographs; newspaper clippings
        - Loose scrapbook material, circa 1950-1961 (Box 240 (Oversize), Folder 2745-2746)
          Includes drawings by Richard Banks and a series of articles by Alfred G. Aronowitz on Fire Island published in The New York Post (1959)
        - Erotic cartoons, undated (Box 224, Folder 2605)
          Album containing colored cartoon clippings (likely 19th century)
    - Fania Marinoff
      - Acting career scrapbook, 1934–1961 (Box 225)
        Includes newspaper clippings, performance programs, and other ephemera relating to FM's acting career; "Fania Marinoff Volume VII" written on spine; bookplate of FM pasted inside front cover
  - Audiovisual Material
    - Sound recordings
      Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Fania Marinoff and Rollo Peters in The Streets of New York, undated (Box 239, Folder 2740)
        Speak-O-Phone aluminum record (one 6-inch disc)
      - Carl Van Vechten "barking" with Max Ewing at the piano, 1929 (Box 239, Folder 2741-2742)
        Speak-O-Phone aluminum records (two 7-inch discs)
      - Original disc housing, undated (Box 239, Folder 2743)
        Two mailing containers from Dorothy Caruso Recording Studio, 143 East 62nd Street New York, New York
  - Financial, Legal, and Medical Records
    - Financial Records
      - Bank books, 1961, undated (Box 226, Folder 2606)
        Two bank books from account at The Bank of New York
      - Cancelled checks, miscellaneous, 1911–1941 (Box 226, Folder 2607)
        Includes checks to Philip Moeller William Robinson, Mabel Luhan, Avery Hopwood, among others
      - Credit card and brochure, undated (Box 226, Folder 2608)
      - Receipts (Box 226)
        - Spink and Gaborc, 1941-1962, undated (Box 226, Folder 2609-2611)
        - Stationery and bookplates, 1940–1942 (Box 226, Folder 2612)
        - Miscellaneous, 1921-1961, undated (Box 226, Folder 2613-2614)
      - Record book, circa 1940-1961 (Box 226, Folder 2615)
        Includes income from stocks, publications, etc., and various expenditures
      - Tax Records
        - 1933, 1935
          - Correspondence (Box 227, Folder 2616)
            Correspondence with "Mr. Cassidy"
        - 1958
          - Correspondence and tax forms, 1958–1959 (Box 227, Folder 2617-2618)
          - Cancelled checks, 1958 (Box 227, Folder 2619-2620)
          - Receipts, 1957–1958 (Box 227, Folder 2621)
        - 1959
          - Correspondence and tax forms, 1960–1961 (Box 227, Folder 2622)
          - Cancelled checks, 1959 (Box 227, Folder 2623-2624)
          - Receipts, 1959 (Box 227, Folder 2625)
        - 1960
          - Correspondence and notes, 1961 (Box 227, Folder 2626)
          - Cancelled checks, 1960 (Box 227, Folder 2627-2628)
          - Receipts, 1960 (Box 227, Folder 2629)
        - 1961
          - Cancelled checks, 1961 (Box 228, Folder 2630-2634)
          - Cancelled checks--personal gifts, 1961 (Box 228, Folder 2635)
          - Receipts, 1961 (Box 228, Folder 2636-2640)
          - Receipts--donations, 1961 (Box 228, Folder 2641)
          - Gifts to libraries, 1961 (Box 228, Folder 2642)
          - Notes regarding gifts, 1961 (Box 228, Folder 2643)
          - Royalties and dividends, 1961 (Box 228, Folder 2644)
        - 1962
          - Cancelled checks, 1962 (Box 228, Folder 2645-2646)
          - Investment statements, 1962 (Box 229, Folder 2647)
          - Notes and gift lists, 1962 (Box 229, Folder 2648)
          - Receipts, 1962 (Box 229, Folder 2649-2650)
        - 1963
          - Cancelled checks, 1963 (Box 229, Folder 2651-2653)
          - Dividend statements, 1963 (Box 229, Folder 2654)
          - Receipts, 1963 (Box 229, Folder 2655-2656)
        - 1964
          - Cancelled checks, 1964 (Box 229, Folder 2657-2661)
          - Receipts, 1964 (Box 230, Folder 2662-2664)
        - 1965
          - Bank receipts, 1965 (Box 230, Folder 2665)
    - Legal documents
      - Marriage certificate, 1914 October 21 (Box 230, Folder 2666)
        Includes typescript note from CVV to the Stamford, Connecticut marriage bureau applying for a marriage license, dated 1914 October 1, with autograph manuscript note response from the Stamford Town Clerk on bottom of sheet
      - Passports, 1949–1963 (Box 230, Folder 2667)
        Passports of CVV and FM
      - Drafts of letters regarding CVV's will and literary and photographic executors, 1957, 1959, undated (Box 230, Folder 2668)
        Includes typescript drafts from CVV to FM, Donald Gallup, Joseph Solomon, and Saul Mauriber
    - Medical Records
      - Carl Van Vechten, 1947-1957, undated (Box 230, Folder 2669)
        Includes CVV's routine medical test results and weight reduction diets
  - Notebooks
    Several notebooks contain notes by CVV indicating that they should be given to the New York Public Library after this death. However, the volumes were sent to Yale with his other papers and his executors determined that they would remain at Yale.
    - Carl Van Vechten
      - Expense account book, Paris, 1908 June 28–1909 April 8 (Box 231, Folder 2670)
        Includes entries of expenses incurred and payments received from The New York Times
      - Articles cabled from Paris, 1908 July 16–1909 April 8 (Box 231, Folder 2671)
        Includes subject of articles written and cost of cable sent from Paris to The New York Times
      - European theaters and performances, undated (Box 231, Folder 2672)
        Includes descriptions of theaters and performances in Germany, Belgium, and the Netherlands
      - Goods and services notebook, undated (Box 231, Folder 2673)
        Alphabetized record book containing names of shops, services, doctors, etc., from "art books" to "zipper service"
      - Bibliographical notebooks
        - Writings by CVV, 1917 October 15–1924 (Box 231, Folder 2674)
          Notebook containing lists of writings by and about CVV dating from 1901-1924
        - "Carl Van Vechten, a personal record, from January 24, 1925, Volume II", 1925–1964 (Box 231, Folder 2675)
          Notebook containing lists of writings by and about CVV; with typescript, printed, and autograph notes; loose notes from volume foldered with notebook
        - Annotated proofs, undated (Box 241 (Oversize), Folder 2750)
          Proofs of printed bibliographies from CVV publications, with autograph manuscript annotations removed from "Carl Van Vechten, a personal record, from January 24, 1925, Volume II"
        - Published photographs, 1932 November–1963 (Box 231, Folder 2676)
          Notebook containing list of publications and exhibitions that included CVV photographs; loose notes and letter from The McCall Company (1935 April 30) from volume foldered with notebook
      - Photographs of New England, undated (Box 231, Folder 2677)
        Pocket notebook containing list of photographs taken during a trip to New England
      - Sitters and subjects of CVV photographs, circa 1938 (Box 231, Folder 2678)
        Two notebooks containing alphabetical list of sitters, coded by profession and race, with key on front paste down of one of the volumes; photograph dates (1932-1938); and photograph numbers
        - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 232, Folder 2679-2680)
          Four pocket notebooks and calendars containing miscellaneous notes
    - Fania Marinoff
      - German lessons, 1938–1939 (Box 232, Folder 2681-2685)
        Typescript German lessons and manuscript notes
        Gift of Leo Lerman, 1987
      - "Letters and notes of sympathy and condolence on the death of my husband", [1964-1965] (Box 232, Folder 2686)
        Small binder containing names of individuals who sent FM condolences after the death of CVV; accompanied by photocopied thank you note on FM letterhead (1964 December 31), and a pocket memo book containing another list of names
  - Notes and Lists
    - Carl Van Vechten
      - Lists of correspondents, 1908–1945 (Box 232, Folder 2687)
      - Inscriptions from books given to CVV, 1934–1961 (Box 232, Folder 2688)
      - Lists and notes regarding CVV photographs, undated (Box 232, Folder 2689-2690)
      - Lists of libraries and museums holding CVV photograph collections, undated (Box 232, Folder 2691-2692)
        Manuscript lists, photocopies, in the hand of Saul Mauriber
      - List of phonograph recordings, undated (Box 232, Folder 2693)
        List, typescript, of phonograph recordings, including "special" recordings of FM, Rollo Peters, and CVV "barking" with piano accompaniment Max Ewing
      - Lists of recipients of books inscribed by CVV, undated (Box 232, Folder 2694)
      - Index card catalog of CVV's book collection
        Incomplete catalog of books owned by CVV, with notes regarding acquisition and provenance
        - Ade - Mencken, undated (Box 233)
        - Mendés - My Maiden Effort, undated (Box 234)
      - Notes regarding European travel, 1944, 1949, undated (Box 235, Folder 2695)
      - Notes regarding gifts and telegrams sent, 1956, 1959, undated (Box 235, Folder 2696)
      - Notes on index cards regarding works of art and artists, undated (Box 235, Folder 2697)
      - "Sayings and quotations", undated (Box 235, Folder 2698)
      - Notes regarding books and works of art, undated (Box 235, Folder 2699)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 235, Folder 2700)
    - Fania Marinoff
      - List of theatrical roles, undated (Box 235, Folder 2701)
      - Note regarding the disposition of CVV's books, undated (Box 235, Folder 2702)
      - Notes regarding FM's theatrical tour with the Blanche Walsh Company, 1901–1902 (Box 235, Folder 2703)
      - Inscriptions from books given to FM from CVV, 1913–1948 (Box 235, Folder 2704)
  - Ephemera and Objects
    - Ephemera
      - Carl Van Vechten
        - Awards and Citations
          - New York Public Library citation, 1960 June 15 (Box 240 (Oversize), Folder 2747)
          - Yale University Medal, 1961 (Box 240 (Oversize), Folder 2748)
        - Baggage labels, undated (Box 235, Folder 2705)
          Airline, ship, and hotel labels
        - Business cards, 1938, undated (Box 235, Folder 2706)
        - Certificates, 1923–1942 (Box 235, Folder 2707)
          Membership certificates from American Mercury, NAACP, and Negro Actors Guild of America; literacy certificate from the University of the State of New York
        - Dinner party menus, 1920–1938 (Box 235, Folder 2708)
        - Guest lists, undated (Box 235, Folder 2709)
          Typescript mimeograph guest lists for a Shakespeare luncheon and a cocktail party attended by CVV and FM
        - Recipes, undated (Box 235, Folder 2710)
        - Travel
          Business cards, receipts, letters, and other ephemera relating to travel taken by CVV
          - Budapest, undated (Box 235, Folder 2711)
          - Budapest, undated (Box 241 (Oversize), Folder 2751)
            Map of the city
          - California and New Mexico, 1928–1950 (Box 235, Folder 2712)
          - Caribbean, 1951, undated (Box 235, Folder 2713)
          - Germany, 1930 (Box 235, Folder 2714)
          - Iowa, undated (Box 240 (Oversize), Folder 2749)
            Maps of Linn and Washington Counties, Iowa, with history of Linn County;, both clipped from an unidentified publication
          - Italy, 1931–1949 (Box 235, Folder 2715)
          - London, 1929–1930 (Box 235, Folder 2716)
          - Paris and France, 1928–1949 (Box 236, Folder 2717)
          - Spain, 1935 (Box 236, Folder 2718)
        - Unsent birthday cards, undated (Box 236, Folder 2719)
        - Van Vechten collection bookplates, undated (Box 236, Folder 2720)
        - Van Vechten holiday, anniversary, and change of address cards, 1938–1951 (Box 236, Folder 2721)
        - Wine labels for "Premier Cru Vanvechtiana", 1954 March 20 (Box 236, Folder 2722)
          Labels made presumably for FM's birthday
        - Miscellaneous ephemera, 1879-1943, undated (Box 236, Folder 2723)
      - Fania Marinoff
        - Biographical article, 1966 (Box 236, Folder 2724)
          Photocopy of biographical entry for FM from The Biographical Encyclopaedia and Who's Who of the American Theatre (New York: James H. Heineman, Inc., 1966)
        - Dollar bill inscribed to FM by Mischa Elman, undated (Box 236, Folder 2725)
          With typed description
        - Funeral guest registers, 1964, 1971 (Box 236, Folder 2726-2727)
          Guest registers for funerals for CVV and FM
        - Membership cards, 1928, 1942, undated (Box 236, Folder 2728)
          Includes cards for the Actors' Equity Association and the American Theatre Wing War Service
        - Miscellaneous ephemera, undated (Box 236, Folder 2729)
    - Objects
      - Carl Van Vechten
        - American Theatre Wing "Captain" armband, undated (Box 237, Folder 2730)
        - Custom box for CVV collection material (Box 327)
          Floral fabric box (empty); previously containing Gertrude Stein correspondence to CVV
        - Custom boxes for CVV collection material (Box 328)
          Two custom boxes (empty); made for CVV collections of Autographs and James Weldon Johnson Pamphlets
        - Engraving plates, undated (Box 237, Folder 2731)
          Includes plates for CVV name cards
        - Engraving plates, undated (Box 238)
          Includes engraving plates mounted on metal blocks; plates for Covarrubias engraving of "A prediction to Carl from Covarrubias" and "As Mr. Van Vechten Gooses a Gold Fish"
        - Penwiper, undated (Box 237, Folder 2732)
          Ink pen wiper in the form of a cat; with envelope with typed note: "This was Anna M.[arble] P.[ollock]'s own pen-wiper"
        - Portfolio for CVV collection material (Box 329 (Oversize))
          Custom folio (empty)
        - Rubber ink stamps and embosser, undated (Box 237, Folder 2733-2736)
          Includes stamp and embosser reading: "Photograph by Carl Van Vechten"
      - Fania Marinoff
        - American Theatre Wing pins, circa 1942-1945 (Box 237, Folder 2737)
          Includes pins for Stage Door Canteen, Club for Merchant Seamen, and Service Womens Tea Dances
        - Rubber ink stamp, undated (Box 237, Folder 2738)
          Stamp reads: "F. Marinoff"
        - Travel wallet, undated (Box 237, Folder 2739)
- Art, 1866-1964; Series IV; 19.0; 12 boxes + 11 art, 9 broadsides, and 2 broadsides oversize
  Arranged alphabetically by artist, followed by miscellaneous works and art reproductions.
  Series IV, Art, includes portraits and caricatures of Carl Van Vechten by Martha Baker, Romaine Brooks, Miguel Covarrubias, Ruth Hammond, Florine Stettheimer, and others; watercolor drawings of Fania Marinoff in theatrical roles by Robert Evans Locher and Rollo Peters, and a statuette of Marinoff in fabric and wax by Luis Hidalgo. Additional works in a variety of media include numerous works by James Purdy; designs for Van Vechten publications by Robert Evans Locher, Ronald McRae, and Prentiss Taylor; costume and set designs; greeting card art, including a Valentine from Carrie Stettheimer; and an artist's book believed to be created by Donald Windham. Works by unidentified artists, miscellaneous prints, and art reproductions are also included.
  - Baker, Martha Susan
    - "Carl Van Vechten", undated (Box 254 (Art))
      Oil
  - Banks, Richard
    - "Carl Van Vechten", 1961 (Box 255 (Art))
  - Barton, Ralph
    - [Design for dust jacket for The Tattooed Countess], undated (Box 253 (Oversize), Folder 2828)
      Ink and watercolor; with two copies of printed poster with same design for the exhibition, "Carl Van Vechten, 1880-1964: Cultural Contributions of a Century" at Kirkwood Community College, Cedar Rapids, Iowa, 1980
  - Bevan, Frank Poole
    - [Costume rendering], 1936 (Box 249, Folder 2799)
      Watercolor rendering of 17th century male, possibly for a production of Le Bourgeois gentilhomme
  - Brackenridge, Hugh
    - "Greetings", undated (Box 253 (Oversize), Folder 2829)
      Woodcut, colored, of madonna and child with bird
  - Brooks, Romaine
    - [Carl Van Vechten], undated (Box 256 (Art))
    - [Muriel Draper], undated (Box 257 (Art))
  - Cabell, Ballard Hartwell
    - "Ride of the Valkerie", circa 1951 (Box 242 (Oversize), Folder 2752)
      Watercolor
    - "Smoky Rhythms", circa 1951 (Box 242 (Oversize), Folder 2753)
  - Cotton, William
    - "Gerald Musgrave, Esq.", undated (Box 242 (Oversize), Folder 2754)
      Ink
  - Cotton, John
    - [Caricatures], 1939, undated (Box 249, Folder 2800)
      Three caricatures, graphite, of Doris Keane, Olga Nethersole, and an unidentified woman
  - Covarrubias, Miguel
    - "As Mr. Van Vechten Gooses a Gold Fish", undated (Box 242 (Oversize), Folder 2755)
      See also Series III, Box 238, engraving plate
    - "As Mr. Van Vechten Gooses a Gold Fish", undated (Box 251)
      Ink; with frame
    - [Caricatures and sketches], undated (Box 249, Folder 2801)
      Graphite; mulitple caricatures and sketches on four leaves; with color print of Blanche Knopf by Covarrubias
    - "Carl Van Vechten Caricature No. IV", undated (Box 242 (Oversize), Folder 2756)
      Graphite
    - [Christmas cards], 1925, undated (Box 249, Folder 2802)
      Watercolor; three drawings with holiday greetings
    - [Portrait of Carl Van Vechten], undated (Box 242 (Oversize), Folder 2757)
      Tempera
    - "A prediction to Carl from Covarrubias", undated (Box 249, Folder 2803)
      Reproduction of engraving (2 copies)
  - Fabri, Ralph
    - "Salute to Carl Van Vechten", 1944 (Box 258 (Art))
      Watercolor and ink with inscription, "We the bus boys, hosts and hostesses of the Stage Door Canateen salute our Captain Carl Van Vechten," with circa 25 signatures
  - George, George
    - [Sketches], 1946-1947, undated (Box 243 (Oversize), Folder 2758)
      Five watercolor and ink greeting cards
  - Hammond, Ruth
    - [Caricature of Carl Van Vechten], 1922 (Box 243 (Oversize), Folder 2759)
  - Hidalgo, Luis
    - [Fania Marinoff], undated (Box 259 (Art))
      Statuette in fabric and wax, in glass and metal frame
  - Horgan, Paul
    - "Madame Nattatorrini", undated (Box 249, Folder 2804)
  - Ilona, R.S.
    - [Carl Van Vechten], undated (Box 260 (Art))
      Pastel
  - Johnson, Bradford
    - [Mabel Dodge Luhan], undated (Box 249, Folder 2805)
      Reproduction of graphite drawing
  - Justema, William
    - "Max Ewing", undated (Box 243 (Oversize), Folder 2760)
      Mixed media
  - Karidis, Jerome
    - [Collage], 1955 (Box 243 (Oversize), Folder 2761)
  - Karson, Nat
    - [Mask for the Duchess in Alice in Wonderland ], 1936 (Box 243 (Oversize), Folder 2762)
      Watercolor; with inscription to CVV by Karson
  - Kauffer, E. McKnight (Edward McKnight)
    - [Caricature of Carl Van Vechten], 1930 (Box 261 (Art))
      Charcoal
  - Locher, Robert Evans
    - "Fania Marinoff as Columbine" (Box 243 (Oversize), Folder 2763)
      Watercolor from a production of Behind a Watteau Picture at the Greenwich Village Theater, New York, 1917 November
    - [Frontispiece for Blind-Bow Boy ], undated (Box 243 (Oversize), Folder 2764)
      Ink and watercolor
    - "Vaudeville", undated (Box 243 (Oversize), Folder 2765)
      Blueprint drawing of "Vaudeville" pencil line drawing by Charles Demuth, circa 1918
    - "Watch Your Step!", undated (Box 243 (Oversize), Folder 2766)
      Ink and watercolor; with printer's annotations
    - "What Can Happen in an Inn That Is Black and White", undated (Box 243 (Oversize), Folder 2767)
  - Loy, Mina
    - "Carlo", undated (Box 253 (Oversize), Folder 2830)
      Graphite drawing of Carl Van Vechten
  - Lucioni, Luigi
    - [Etchings], 1943, 1945 (Box 249, Folder 2806)
      Two etchings sent to CVV and FM as Christmas greetings
  - McRae, Ronald
    - [Design for dust jacket for Spider Boy ], undated (Box 244 (Oversize), Folder 2768)
      Ink and watercolor?
  - Miller, Arthur
    - [Figure drawing], 1940 (Box 265 (Broadside))
      Watercolor; inscribed "to Carl Van Vechten from Henry Miller, Bowling Green, Va 9/40"
  - Penfield, Edward
    - [Prints], 1879, 1899 (Box 244 (Oversize), Folder 2769-2770)
      Lithographs; from poster calendar (1879), and Harper's magazine (March 1899)
  - Peters, Rollo
    - [Fania Marinoff in Streets of New York ], undated (Box 244 (Oversize), Folder 2771)
  - Priebe, Karl
    - [Drawing of a woman], 1951 (Box 249, Folder 2807)
      Watercolor; with note to CVV
    - "Merry Christmas; Spider Boy by Carl Van Vechten", undated (Box 249, Folder 2808)
  - Purdy, James
    - [Abstract figure drawing], 1955 (Box 266 (Broadside))
      Felt-tip pen
    - [Abstract figure drawing], 1956 (Box 267 (Broadside))
    - [Abstract figure drawing], 1956 (Box 268 (Broadside))
    - [Abstract figure drawings], 1956 (Box 269 (Broadside))
    - [Abstract figure drawing], 1956 (Box 270 (Broadside))
    - [Abstract figure drawing], 1956 (Box 271 (Broadside))
    - [Abstract figure drawing], 1955 (Box 274 (Broadside oversize))
    - [Abstract figure drawing], 1955 (Box 275 (Broadside oversize))
      Ink and felt-tip pen